Seamus Heaney papers, 1951-2004
Emory University
- Photographs, 1951-2003, Series 5; Boxes 90 – 93; OP1
  - Shop [Bearpond] window in Montpelier featuring sign congratulating Seamus Heaney for Novel Prize, ca. 1995 (Box 92, Folder 64)
  - Bookshop window featuring books by Seamus Heaney translated into Spanish, color snapshot, ca. 1995 (Box 92, Folder 65)
  - Painting by Joan Ramsden, color snapshot, ca. 1997 (Box 92, Folder 66)
  - Bicycle and flax sheaves for roof thatching, color snapshot by Keith Chadwick, June 1998 (Box 92, Folder 67)
  - Painting of Seamus Heaney by Jeannie Summerall, two color snapshots, ca. 1999 (Box 92, Folder 68)
  - Sign post marking Heaney St. in Eastwood, (New South Wales, Australia), color snapshot, ca. 1999 (Box 92, Folder 69)
  - Display in steel mill in Soderfors (Sweden) featuring Seamus Heaney's "The Forge" from Door into the Dark, color snapshot, ca. 200 (Box 92, Folder 70)
  - Quilt by Linda Lister to which Seamus Heaney contributed tracings of his hands, six color snapshots, 2001 (Box 92, Folder 71)
  - Art objects in the Lake Biwa Canal Museum (Kyoto), three color snapshots, 2002 (Box 92, Folder 72)
  - Paintings by Tony [?] three color snapshots, 2002 (Box 92, Folder 73)
  - Drawing ["Poolbeg"], in stained glass form by Katharine Lamb, color snapshot, ca. 2002 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Book displayed for Redfoxpress promotion, two color snapshots, undated (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Books by Seamus Heaney displayed on table, four color snapshots, undated (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Segments of mono-print by Robert Tilling, nine color snapshots, undated (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Portrait [Seamus Heaney?] by unknown artist, color photograph, undated (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Portrait of Brian Friel painted by Basil Blackshaw, color snapshot, undated (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Marker for Philip and Jill Donnellan, including poem by Seamus Heaney, color snapshot, undated (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified sculpture of [gazelle?] with wings, color snapshot, undated (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Sculpture of a horse, color snapshot, undated (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of paintings in the Ulster Museum (Belfast), thirty-five black and white photographs, undated (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Landscapes and castles [Ireland] photographed by Michael Parker, fifteen black and white snapshots (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Places
  - "Hyperbole," seaside cottage of Chris Wallace-Crabbe (Australia), ca. 1993 (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - Joseph Brodsky's gravesite, San Machele (Venice), color snapshot, 21 June 1997 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Frozen waterfall at unknown site in Nora (Sweden), color snapshot, December 1998 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Waterfall at unknown site in Nora (Sweden), color snapshot, ca.1999 (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - Teach Synge, Inis Meain (Aran Islands), two color snapshots, November 1999 (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Landscape in Derrynane, Ireland (County Kerry), color snapshot, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Yorgo Seferis' childhood home, now a hotel, near Izmir (Turkey), color snapshot, 2001 (Box 93, Folder 18)
  - Views of Bologna (Italy), three color snapshots, ca. 2001 (Box 93, Folder 19)
  - Ruins of Kilcolman Castle (County Cork, Ireland), two color snapshots, ca. 2001 (Box 93, Folder 20)
  - Unidentified location with view of frozen stream, color snapshot, ca. 2002 (Box 93, Folder 21)
  - Ariel photograph of property near Lynchburg (Tennessee), black and white photograph by William Grogan, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 22)
  - Landscape in [Armagh, Northern Ireland?], color snapshot, ca. 2002 (Box 93, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 93, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous slides (Box 93, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous negatives (Box 93, Folder 26)
- Audio-Visual materials, 1994-2002, Series 6; Boxes 94 - 95
  The series consists of a small number of audiocassettes, videocassettes, and compact discs from 1994-2002. These are primarily recordings of public appearances and readings by Heaney. Also included are miscellaneous recordings related to poetry which were sent to Heaney by acquaintances.
  Arranged by record type.
  - Audiocassettes
  - "Goosebumps and Tingles," presenter: Seamus Caulfield, compiler: Sheila O'Callaghan, recorded from Ireland RTE Radio 1, includes a reading by Seamus Heaney of his poem, "Belderg," undated (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - William Butler Yeats reading his own poetry, recorded from unknown source, sent to Seamus Heaney by Peter O'Shaughnessy, undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Seamus Heaney reading at the University of Melbourne (Australia), October 1994 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - "Seamus Heaney at Melbourne Writer's Festival, side one: "Evening with Edna O'Brien," and discussion of religious poetry: "God Moves in Mysterious Metres," side two: continuation of side one discussion and "Poems Read on BBC Television broadcast presented by Melvyn Bragg, includes Seamus Heaney reading his poetry, 1994 [digitized: Emory:b7rdr, b7rfw] (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - "The Open Mind," BBC Radio, celebrating the achievement of Seamus Heaney in his winning the Nobel Prize for Literature. Includes broadcast of Heaney's opening address ["Words Alone"] to the World Congress of the International Reading Association (Dublin), 27 July 1982, taped from radio broadcast, 1995 (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - "The Box Seat," second in the International Voices Poetry series, presented by David Britton, Australian Broadcasting Company, features Seamus Heaney, reading his poetry. Recorded at the 1994 Melbourne Writers Festival, broadcast ca. 1995 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Meridian Radio documentary on Joseph Brodsky from the series Meridian Features, presenter: Elizabeth Robson; producer: Jenny Hargreaves; included is a statement read by Seamus Heaney, February 1996 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Mediumwave, RTE Radio program regarding Irish journalism, includes Seamus Heaney on the art of poetry and journalism, 1 July 1996 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Seeing Things," text by Seamus Heaney and music by Dario Marianelli [for the Rotterdamse Dansegroep], August 1996 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - "Farewell to Stromness," produced by Elizabeth Clark, music by Sir Peter Maxwell Davie. Six poets read their own specially commissioned tributes to George Mackay Brown who died in April 1996. Poets included are Seamus Heaney, Iain Crichton Smith, Liz Lochead, Stewart Conn, Edwina Morgan and Kenneth White, ca. 1997 (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - "Through the Ear of a Raindrop," John Wolf Brennan heXtet, thirteen pieces for six musicians, eight poems and five echoes, includes two poems by Seamus Heaney, 1997 (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - "Viewing the Century," Les Murray talks with Kevin Jackson about rationalism and the dream world, Australian writing and universities, and atrocity in the twentieth century, BBC Radio 3 interview, 13 September 1998 (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - Yeats Poetry, read by Peter O'Shaughnessy, undated (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - Compact Discs
  - "Birdsong," symphonic work by Dominic Crawford Collins, Birdsong Music Productions Ltd. (Wicklow, Ireland), 2000 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - "A Celtic Christian Year in Poetry, Prayer & Song," spoken word, accompanied by Irish Harp includes writings of St. Columcille, Patrick Kavanagh, St. Patrick, Seamus Heaney, John Shea, and Biblical Scriptures, produced and arranged by Mairead Doherty, Aham-chara Records, 2002 (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - Videocassettes
  - "Daedalus en Compostela," [in English], based on a story by Vinsente Risco, Formato: Universidade da Coruna, undated (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - "Vittorio Gassman Reading Dante, Inferno: Canto I-VII," reading in Italian, recorded from television, undated (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - "Professor Seamus Heaney, Honorary Graduate," University of Stirling, Scotland, ca. 28 June 1990 (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - "What Is to be Done? :Three Years of the Fatwa," arranged by Friends and Supporters of Salman Rushdie and produced by BBC Television. Includes live presentations by Tom Stoppard, Gunter Grass, Martin Amis, and Salman Rushdie and filmed presentations by Nadine Gordimer, Seamus Heaney, Derek Walcott, and Edward Said, 14 February 1992 (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - "Bobbie Hanvey Photo Exhibition," launched by David Hammond, recorded from television, Reverse Angle Productions, (Belfast), September 1995 (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - "St. Columb's College", (Derry, Northern Ireland), includes short segment on Seamus Heaney, RTE Nationwide (Belfast), 1995 (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - "The Live Experiences: Phil Coulter and His Orchestra," includes a tribute to Seamus Heaney [reading of The Mid Term Break by Coulter], live recording at University of Limerick Concert, K-Tel Video Products, (Dublin), 1995 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - 1996 Commencement Video," University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Seamus Heaney commencement speaker and honorary degree recipient, 12 May 1996 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - "The Darkest Days: Edward Daly Remembers," parts I and II, Bishop Edward Daly of Derry, relates his recollections of the turmoil in Northern Ireland from the late 1960s through the hunger strikes and violence of the 1980s. Includes film clips of the conflict, RTE news production 1996 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - "The Interview: Bernard MacLaverty," Roisin McAuley talks to Irish writer, Bernard MacLaverty, BBC Northern Ireland [Belfast], 26 November 1997 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - "The Interview: Brian Moore," Roisin McAuley talks to novelist Brian Moore, BBC Northern Ireland [Belfast], 13 December 1997 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - "The Poetry of Seamus Heaney," program 2 from the series Poetry Backpack: Three Poets, narrated by John Hagley, BBC Television, ca. 1997 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - "A Gift of Words: Video Poems from Distinguished New England Poets," presented by 2000 Bridges, Boston University: Hot house Productions, poets include Frank Bidart, Mary Oliver, Donald Hall, and Derek Walcott, 1998 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - "The Edge of Europe," traces the movement of monastic orders to isolated sites in Ireland, produced by David Main, Riochta Productions, 1999 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - "Degree Congregation," University of Birmingham, Seamus Heaney receiving honorary degree, 12 July 2000 (Box 95, Folder 9)
- Personal papers, 1965-2001, Series 7; Boxes 96 - 97
  Personal papers include a small number of contracts, calendars schedules and itineraries and other miscellaneous personal papers from 1965-2001.
  - Contracts
  - BBC contracts: radio, 1965-1973 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - BBC contracts: television, 1966-1994 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - BBC contracts: radio, 1974-1979 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - BBC contracts: radio, 1980-1999 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous contracts, 1960s-1970s (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous contracts, 1980s (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous contracts, 1990-2001 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Calendars
  - Academic year assignment book, 1976-1977 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous calendar sheets, 1999 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous calendar sheets, year not designated (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Schedules and itineraries
  - Hereford College of Education, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous itineraries and schedules, 1985-2002 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Michigan Poetry Circuit, Spring, 1971 (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - Lecture schedule, 23 February-13 March 1980 (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - Greece trip, 1997 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Other personal papers
  - Blank stationery and response cards (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - Curriculum vitae (Box 96, Folder 17)
  - Directories and lists (Box 96, Folder 18)
  - Harvard University, 1981-1993 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Notes, memoranda, and lists; various dates [1 of 3] (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Notes, memoranda, and lists; various dates [2 of 3] (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Notes, memoranda, and lists; various dates [3 of 3] (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Oxford University, 1989 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Queens University, Belfast, 1970 (Box 97, Folder 6)
- Writings by Seamus Heaney, 1966-2004, Series 8; Boxes 98 – 102; OP2 – OP8
  The writings of Seamus Heaney consist of works of poetry, translation, and prose from the early 1960's-2004. Included in the group of poetry and translation are holograph poems, some typescript poems with extensive revision and a few untitled poems and fragments. Most are undated and all have been arranged alphabetically. The works of prose include addresses and lectures, British Broadcasting Corporation scripts, eulogies, notes, other prose, and editing projects. The majority of the prose works are dated and all have been arranged chronologically. Early prose consists of a small number of graded essays written by Heaney as a student. Most notable of the editing projects in the series is one shared with Ted Hughes, The School Bag, which includes lists of poems, correspondence, and files of photocopied items under consideration for the anthology.
  Organized into two subseries: (8.1) Poetry and translations and (8.2) Prose.
  - Poetry and translations, 1969-2003, Subseries 8.1; Box 98
    Arranged by record type, then in alphabetical order.
    - Poetry
    - "Angle," photocopied typescript with complete holograph rewriting (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - "Broagh," photocopied draft from early notebook (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - "Canopy," typescript with holograph revisions, two drafts and relating correspondence with Myra Mayman and David Ward, March 1996 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - "The Comet," [early draft of "The Comet at Lullwater,"], typescript, ca. 2003 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - "The Errand," early draft, typescript (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - A Family Album [?], holograph poems and prose, ca. 1970s (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - "Far Away" from "The Flight Path" photocopied typescript with holograph revisions and holograph notes on verso (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - "A Flourish for the Prince of Denmark," carbon typescript with one holograph correction (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - "from 'Commencement Verses,'" ["Verses for a Fordham Commencement"], 23 May 1982, typescript with some corrections (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - "The Given Note," [published in Door into the Dark, 1969], holograph draft and notes (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - The Harvest Bow, excerpts, typescript with some corrections and including correspondence between Seamus Heaney and Peter Fallon (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - "Into Acadia," ("from a sonnet sequence in progress"), photocopied typescript, ca. 2001 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - "Keeping Going," [published in The Spirit Level], photocopied typescript (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - "Kosovosummer," early draft from "The Known World," typescript with holograph note (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - "The Loose Box," fragment of early draft, typescript with holograph revisions (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - "Non-U," (in memory of Darcy O'Brien), typescript (Box 98, Folder 16)
    - "On a New Work in the English Tongue," (for Ted Hughes), typescript (Box 98, Folder 17)
    - Opened Ground: Selected Poems, 1966-1996, photocopies from printed sources, suggested contents and related correspondence, 1997 (Box 98, Folder 18)
    - "A Paced Text," typescript draft with many holograph revisions and notes (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - "Real Names ["Dramatis Personae" published in Electric Light], typescript drafts with holograph revisions (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - "Scaffolding," "Storm on the Island," "Lighting the Lamp," "The Old Labourer Regrets," "Young Bachelor," five poems returned to Seamus Heaney with rejection letter from The Times Literary Supplement, ca. 1964 (Box 98, Folder 21)
    - "The Sharping Stone," [published in The Spirit Level, 1996], typescript (Box 98, Folder 22)
    - "The Sharping Stone," galley proof with holograph revisions, 8 June 1995 (Box 98, Folder 23)
    - "A Sofa in the Forties," "The Banagher," "The Fragment" "Exile's Return" (translation), "Testimony," "The Boiling house," "Kevin and the Blackbird," typescripts (Box 98, Folder 24)
    - Station Island, revisions to Section 11, typescript with holograph revisions (Box 98, Folder 25)
    - "The Underground," perfect holograph copy, signed by Seamus Heaney, on stationary printed with "Folger Poetry Programs 1984-85" (Box 98, Folder 26)
    - Untitled poem with first line: "This shuttle, David, is a symbol…," holograph draft (Box 98, Folder 27)
    - Untitled poems, holograph drafts (Box 98, Folder 28)
    - "Valentines Eve 2000," typescript inscribed and signed by Seamus Heaney (Box 98, Folder 29)
    - "W.H. Auden, 1907-1993," "Marching Season," "A Norman Simile," "I.IV.'97," "The Lesson," typescripts with some holograph revisions and notes (Box 98, Folder 30)
    - Poetry fragments (Box 98, Folder 31)
    - Translations
    - Beowulf, typescript, p. 14, ca. 1999 (Box 98, Folder 32)
    - Beowulf, photocopied holograph draft of translation, 2 pp., ca. 1999 (Box 98, Folder 33)
    - Beowulf, draft of one sheet with holograph corrections (Box 98, Folder 34)
    - "Brightness of Brightness," ("The Glamsured"), poem by Aodhagan O Rathaille, translated by Seamus Heaney, typescript with holograph revisions, undated (Box 98, Folder 35)
    - "Colmcille the Scribe," translated from eleventh century Irish by Seamus Heaney, typescript (Box 98, Folder 36)
    - "The Clay Pipes," from the Irish of Cathal O Searcaigh, typescript with revisions and notes (Box 98, Folder 37)
    - "Lacrima," photocopied from the printed version with holograph translation in margins (Box 98, Folder 38)
    - "Orpheus and Eurydice," (Ovid, Metamorphoses, Book X), telefacsimile with holograph revisions, ca. 1993 (Box 98, Folder 39)
    - "Poet to Blacksmith," Eoghan Rua O'Suilleahnain's instructions to Seamus MacGearailt, typescript with holograph revisions (Box 98, Folder 40)
    - "Proper Names," translation of Romanian poet Marin Sorescu's poem, entire poem included in typescript fragment of address by Heaney, unknown location and undated (Box 98, Folder 41)
    - "Ugolino," (from Dante, Inferno XXXII and XXXIII), photocopied typescript with revisions (Box 98, Folder 42)
    - "You who opt for English ways," translation of Laoiseach Mac An Bhaird’s 16th-century poem, holograph draft and typescript draft with holograph revisions (Box 98, Folder 43)
  - Prose, 1966-2004, Subseries 8.2; Box 98 - 102; OP 2-8
    - Addresses/Lectures
    - Opening address, World Reading Conference, holograph fragment, ca. 1982 (Box 98, Folder 44)
    - Holograph draft of introduction to reading of "Digging" at Bates College commencement, 26 May 1986 with commencement program (Box 98, Folder 45)
    - "The Sweetest Dream in Robert Frost," conclusion of second lecture as Professor of Poetry at Oxford University, holograph with revisions, 26 October 1989 (Box 98, Folder 46)
    - The Crewe[i]an Oration, Oxford University, typescript with holograph corrections, 19 June 1991, with draft copy of the introduction of the oration and photocopied introduction from Oxford University Gazette (Box 98, Folder 47)
    - Irish Society Michaelmas Dinner address, Oxford University, 30 November 1992, holograph, with signed menu (Box 98, Folder 48)
    - "Irelantis: Exhibition opening at Anya von Gosseln Gallery," typescript address, 28 March 1995 (Box 98, Folder 49)
    - Hughie O'Donoghue Exhibition, Kilkenny, address for exhibition opening, typescript with holograph revisions, 16 August 1997 (Box 98, Folder 50)
    - "Remarks at the Restoration Dinner 1999," [Magdalen College, Oxford], holograph manuscript, signed (Box 98, Folder 51)
    - Untitled after-dinner remarks, University of Pennsylvania commencement weekend, typescript with holograph corrections, 21 May 2000 (Box 98, Folder 52)
    - "Harvard Commencements Readings," three drafts, typescript with some holograph revisions, 8 June 2000 (Box 98, Folder 53)
    - "Student Writing Awards," Purdue U (Box 98, Folder 54)
    - Untitled speech presented as guest of honor at dinner sponsored by The Ireland Funds of France (Paris), typescript and holograph manuscript, April 2, 2002 (Box 98, Folder 55)
    - "Speech at Banquet in Town Hall," Stockholm, 19 September 2003 (Box 98, Folder 56)
    - "Title Deeds: Translating a Classic," lecture, American Philosophical Society, 23 April 2004 (Box 98, Folder 57)
    - "Doing Time: An Apology for Poetry," holograph notes, undated (Box 98, Folder 58)
    - Introduction of Melvyn Bragg, typescript with holograph notes and corrections, undated (Box 98, Folder 59)
    - Lecture on periphery art and Edwin Muir, holograph draft, undated (Box 98, Folder 60)
    - "Robert Fitzgerald: Memorial Address," holograph draft with two typescript copies, undated (Box 98, Folder 61)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation scripts
    - January Review, "The Arts in Ireland," photocopied typescript 23 January 1973 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Explorations: "Otherness," typescript, ca. 1973 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Explorations: "Words Failed Me…," typescript, ca. 1973 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Explorations: "The Long Garden," typescript, ca. 1973 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Explorations: "Bitter Honey," typescript, ca. 1973 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Explorations: "Fields of Praise," typescript with holograph corrections, ca. 1973 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Explorations: "The Chilly Sun," typescript with holograph revisions, ca. 1973 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Explorations: "A Gallous Story," holograph manuscript with typescript book extracts, ca. 1973 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Explorations: "Over the Bridge," holograph manuscript, ca. 1973 (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Ulster in Focus, "Bogland," carbon typescript with holograph revisions and shot list, 11 February 1976 (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - Today and Yesterday in Northern Ireland: "The Mermaid," photocopied typescript with holograph revisions 23 February 1976 (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Explorations II: "Call My Brother Back," photocopied typescript, 12 January 1978 (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Explorations II: "The Emperor of Ice Cream," photocopied typescript, 19 January 1978 (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - Explorations II: "Of Mice and Men," photocopied typescript, 26 January 1978` (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - Today and Yesterday in Northern Ireland: "Thomas Moore I", photocopied typescript, 21 January 1979 (Box 99, Folder 15)
    - Today and Yesterday in Northern Ireland: "Thomas Moore II," photocopied typescript, 23 March 1979 (Box 99, Folder 16)
    - Time for Verse, program 1, holograph notes with duplicated transcript, 1979 [1 of 6] (Box 99, Folder 17)
    - Time for Verse, program 2, holograph notes with duplicated transcript, 1979 [2 of 6] (Box 99, Folder 18)
    - Time for Verse, program 3, holograph notes with duplicated transcript, 1979 [3 of 6] (Box 99, Folder 19)
    - Time for Verse, program 4, holograph notes with duplicated transcript, 1979 [4 of 6] (Box 99, Folder 20)
    - Time for Verse, program 5, holograph notes with duplicated transcript, 1979 [5 of 6] (Box 99, Folder 21)
    - Time for Verse, program 6, holograph notes with duplicated transcript, 1979 [6 of 6] (Box 99, Folder 22)
    - "W.B. Yeats: Cast a Cold Eye," typescript of documentary special with Seamus Heaney as narrator, ca. January 1989 (Box 99, Folder 23)
    - Interview with Seamus Heaney, Abeer Parks and James Cook (presenters) for Newsline, BBC Radio Scotland FM, 7 February 2001 (Box 99, Folder 24)
    - Eulogies
    - Eulogy for Gus Martin, photocopied typescript, ca. 1996 (Box 99, Folder 25)
    - Eulogy for Ted Hughes, holograph draft with revisions, November 1998 (Box 99, Folder 26)
    - "Memorial Address" for Ted Hughes, Westminster Abbey, typescript with holograph corrections, 13 May 1999 (Box 99, Folder 27)
    - Eulogy for Geoffrey [?], holograph draft with notes and photocopy of "Afterwards" by Thomas Hardy, undated (Box 99, Folder 28)
    - Eulogy for Ted [Allen?], holograph, undated (Box 99, Folder 29)
    - Notes
    - Holograph notes regarding Irish Catholic/British relationships from the eighteenth century, mid 1960s (Box 100, Folder 1)